fdbl.com 2017-03-08

# Privacy Policies | Fragomen

ONLINE PRIVACY NOTICE

PRIVACY POLICY AND NOTICE

FRAGOMEN SAFE HARBOR PRIVACY POLICY

**COOKIE POLICY**

EFFECTIVE DATE: March 25, 2015

Fragomen, Del Rey, Bernsen & Loewy, LLP, Fragomen Global LLP, Fragomen Global Immigration Services, LLC and their local entities, members and affiliates (collectively, “Fragomen”) use “cookies” on our websites.  Cookies are text files that are placed on your browser, mobile device or computer’s hard drive when you visit certain websites.

**How we use cookies**  
We use cookies to ensure our websites function properly and to improve user experience. We may use cookies to tell us, for example, whether you have visited us before and to help us identify site features in which you may have the greatest interest.

We use “session cookies,” which will expire when you close your browser. We also use “persistent cookies,” which have a set expiration date and will be stored on your browser, mobile device or computer until the date is reached or you delete your cookies.

**What cookies we use**  
Below is a list of the types of cookies used on our websites:

**Session Cookie**  
Our websites use session cookies to maintain information about each visit to our websites and enable essential functionality. This cookie does not contain any personal information and is deleted as soon as you close your web browser.

**Load Balancer Cookie**  
This sessional cookie is essential to help ensure that our websites load efficiently by distributing visits across multiple web servers. The cookie does not contain any personal information and is deleted as soon as you close your web browser.

**Google Analytics**  
We use Google Analytics, a service provided by Google, to help us understand how visitors use our web site. This allows us to improve the quality and content of our websites. 

For further information about the sessional and persistent cookies used as part of Google Analytics, as well as information about how Google uses this information, please see: <https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/types/>

**Changing your cookie preferences**

Most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, be notified when you receive a new cookie, delete existing cookies and block all cookies.  Information is generally located in the ‘options’ or ‘preferences’ menu, or in the ‘Help’ option. Please note, however, that without cookies, you may not be able to take advantage of all our website features.

**Your consent**

By using our website, you consent to our use and placement of cookies as described in this Notice. If you wish to withdraw your consent at any stage, you will need to disable the settings on your browser as described above.

**Updates to our Cookie Notice**

This Cookies Notice may be updated periodically without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our information practices.  We will post a notice on our applicable websites or materials to advise of any significant changes to our Cookies Notice and indicate in the notice when it was most recently updated.  While this Cookies Notice is designed to comply with most data privacy laws and represents “best practices,” in certain countries additional or different procedures not inconsistent with this Cookies Notice may apply as necessary to satisfy local legal requirements.

**How to Contact Us**

If you have any questions or comments about this Cookies Notice, please contact us by email at [dataprivacy@fragomen.com](mailto:dataprivacy@fragomen.com). You also may write to us at:

Attn: Data Privacy Office

Fragomen, Del Rey, Bernsen & Loewy, LLP

90 Matawan Road

P.O. Box 2001

Matawan, New Jersey 07747

USA

**ONLINE PRIVACY NOTICE**

EFFECTIVE DATE: May 10, 2010

Fragomen, Del Rey, Bernsen & Loewy, LLP, Fragomen Global LLP, and their related affiliates and subsidiaries (collectively “Fragomen”) respect your concerns about privacy. This Online Privacy Notice applies only to personal information collected on [http://www.fragomen.com](http://www.fragomen.com/). This notice describes the types of personal information we collect on this website, how we may use that information and with whom we share it. Our Online Privacy Notice also describes the measures we take to protect the security of the information. We also tell you how you can reach us to answer any questions you may have about our online privacy practices.

**INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE IT  **

**Personal Information We Collect About You**  
If you email us through the “Contact Us” link on this site, you may choose to provide personal information to us such as your name, email address, resume or CV. You may choose to provide additional information as well. We use the information you provide to respond to and communicate with you about your questions and comments.

**Information We Collect by Automated Means**  
We may collect certain information by automated means when you visit this website, such as how many users visited the site and the pages accessed. By collecting this information, we learn how to best tailor our websites to our visitors. We collect this information through “cookies” and IP addresses.

**Cookies**  
Like many organizations, we may use “cookies” on this website. Cookies are bits of text that are placed on your computer’s hard drive when you visit certain websites. We may use cookies to tell us, for example, whether you have visited us before or if you are a new visitor and to help us identify site features in which you may have the greatest interest. Cookies may enhance your online experience by saving your preferences while you are visiting a particular site.

Most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, how to be notified when you receive a new cookie, and how to disable existing cookies. Please note, however, that without cookies, you may not be able to take advantage of all our website features.

**Log Files, Usage Data and IP Addresses**  
Log files are web server files (containing information such as domain name or IP address, URL, http response code, or the date and duration of your visit) that are automatically created when an Internet user visits a website. An IP address is a unique identifier that certain electronic devices use to identify and communicate with each other on the Internet. When you visit our website, our servers log your IP address. In combination with other data, this information helps us understand which features are of interest to our visitors and the regions of the world where these visitors are located. In addition, log files help detect disruptions that may interfere with the provision of our website.

**Information we share**

We do not disclose personal information about visitors to this website, except as described here. We will not sell, share, transfer, rent or distribute your information for purposes other than those disclosed here unless required by law or as authorized by you. We may share the information you provide among our subsidiaries and affiliates. We also may share the information with certain service providers we have retained. We take steps to require that service providers protect the information consistently with this Online Privacy Notice. These service providers are authorized to use the information only as necessary to perform services on our behalf or to comply with law or legal process. Where we have knowledge that a service provider processes your personal information in a manner contrary to this Online Privacy Notice, we will take reasonable steps to prevent or stop the processing. In addition, we may disclose information about you (1) if we are required to do so by law or legal process; (2) to law enforcement authorities or other government officials; (3) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity; or (4) if this is necessary to protect the vital interests of any person.

We also reserve the right to transfer personal information about you in the event we sell, transfer or merge all or a portion of the business or assets. Should such a sale, merger or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to try to direct the transferee to use information that is consistent with this Online Privacy Notice.

**How we protect personal information**

We seek to ensure that any personal information that we hold about you is accurate, complete, current and otherwise reliable based on data you provide in order to provide you with access to and services via this website. We seek to collect personal information that is adequate, relevant and not excessive for these purposes.

We maintain appropriate administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect against loss, misuse or unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction of personal information. 

We educate our employees and strive to maintain appropriate standards of conduct with regard to the protection of personal information. 

We take steps to require that third parties who assist in our provision of services abide by all applicable privacy laws and prohibit them from using your information other than in connection with the services they have been engaged to provide. 

**Links to other websites**

Our website may provide links to other websites for your convenience and information. These websites may operate independently from Fragomen. Linked sites may have their own privacy notices or policies, which we strongly suggest you review if you visit any linked websites. To the extent any linked websites you visit are not owned or controlled by Fragomen, we are not responsible for the sites’ content, any use of the sites, or the privacy practices of the sites.

**Updates to our online PRIVACY NOTICE**

This Online Privacy Notice may be updated periodically to reflect new site features or changes in our information practices. We will post a notice on our website to advise of any significant changes to this Online Privacy Notice and indicate in the notice when it was most recently updated. 

**How to Contact Us**

If you have any questions or comments about this Cookies Notice, please contact us by email at [dataprivacy@fragomen.com](mailto:dataprivacy@fragomen.com). You also may write to us at:

Attn: Office of General Counsel   
Fragomen, Del Rey, Bernsen & Loewy, LLP   
90 Matawan Road   
P.O. Box 2001   
Matawan, New Jersey 07747   
USA 

Please see our Legal Notices.

_Last Updated: April 29, 2013

_________________________________

_

**PRIVACY POLICY AND NOTICE**

Fragomen, Del Rey, Bernsen & Loewy, LLP, Fragomen Global LLP, and their related affiliates and subsidiaries (collectively, “ **Fragomen** ”) understand that its clients are concerned about maintaining the privacy and security of the personal information that Fragomen receives and processes on their behalf, and would like such processing to be open and transparent to its clients and their employees. 

Accordingly, this Privacy Policy and Notice (“ **Privacy Notice** ”) is intended to inform you about Fragomen’s online and offline privacy practices and describes the types of personal information we collect, how we may use that information and with whom we may share it in relation to the client services we provide. 

This Privacy Notice also describes the measures we take to protect the security of the information that we receive and process relating to you. 

In addition, we provide information on how to contact us: (1) to access, correct, or delete your personal information; (2) to exercise choice regarding the processing of your personal information in accordance with applicable laws; and (3) to ask any questions you may have about our privacy practices. You may, if you prefer, address any concerns directly to your employer, in those cases where we process your personal information when engaged to do so by corporations or other business groups. Where we refer to “employer” below, it is in these circumstances where corporations or other business groups have engaged us to act. 

**Information We Collect and How We Use It  **

**Personal Information We Collect About You  **  
For purposes of providing immigration consulting and legal services, Fragomen may collect certain personal information about you and, if required, your family members and employer. In certain circumstances, we may not be able to provide you with the immigration consulting or legal services requested by your current or prospective employer (or you, if our services are rendered under a personal written engagement between you and Fragomen) if we are not provided with all relevant personal information. We set forth below the ways in which information may be provided to us and the types of information that may be necessary for immigration services and visa processing. We also tell you the purposes for which we may use the information that we receive. 

**Client Services  **  
For purposes of providing client services, Fragomen may collect and process personal information such as your name, address, telephone number, date of birth, marital status, passport number, employment history, educational background, tax status, employee number, job title and function, and expatriate status. 

We may obtain the personal information from a number of sources, such as online questionnaires and forms you complete. In addition, we may obtain personal information from third-party sources, such as former employers, educational institutions you attended and your current or prospective employer. We use this information to provide immigration consulting and legal services, such as: (1) analyzing, completing and processing immigration, visa and related filings and submissions to relevant government agencies; (2) assisting with relocation and other expatriate issues; and (3) providing access to online case-management tools, where applicable. 

**Pre-employment Verification  **  
Certain countries may require verification of new employees’ employment eligibility at the time of hire. Examples of such requirements include the Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986 (“ **IRCA** ”) in the United States and the Immigration, Asylum & Nationality Act 2006 in the United Kingdom, pursuant to which Fragomen may collect and process personal information such as your name, email address, home address, military service and citizenship status. 

**Information Requests  **  
If you request information about our services, you may choose to provide personal information such as your name, address, email address and telephone number. We use your information to respond to your request. 

**Other Uses of Information  **  
We may use personal information we collect for other purposes, such as client and Fragomen administration, data analytics, and compliance with applicable laws and Fragomen policies and procedures. 

**Sensitive Personal Data  **

Certain categories of personal information may be considered “sensitive” and are subject to a higher level of data protection. These categories may include race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, sex life or sexual orientation, physical or mental health or condition, and data relating to offenses, and/or criminal convictions. 

In the context of the services we provide, Fragomen may collect sensitive personal data in limited circumstances, for example when such data are necessary to comply with the legal obligations of the country in which you are seeking a visa or work permit. For instance, we may need to ask whether you have been previously convicted of any criminal offenses or other personal matters when the local applicable immigration laws would require such data in an application. 

**Information We Collect by Automated Means  **  
We may collect certain information by automated means for our own purposes when you visit our websites or web-based interfaces (e.g., employer-specific IHP, the BUSINESS VISA MATRIX™), such as how many users visited our sites and the pages accessed. By collecting this information, we learn how to best tailor our websites to our visitors. We collect this information through “cookies” and IP addresses. 

**Cookies  **  
Like many organizations, we may use “cookies” on our websites. Cookies are bits of text that are placed on your computer’s hard drive when you visit certain websites. We may use cookies to tell us, for example, whether you have visited us before or if you are a new visitor and to help us identify site features in which you may have the greatest interest. Cookies may enhance your online experience by saving your preferences while you are visiting a particular site. 

Most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, how to be notified when you receive a new cookie, and how to disable existing cookies. Please note, however, that without cookies, you may not be able to take advantage of all our website features. 

**Log files, usage data and IP addresses  **  
Log files are web server files (containing information such as domain name or IP address, URL, http response code, or the date and duration of your visit) that are automatically created when an Internet user visits a website. An IP address is a unique identifier that certain electronic devices use to identify and communicate with each other on the Internet. When you visit our website, our servers log your IP address. In combination with other data, this information helps us understand which features are of interest to our visitors and the regions of the world where these visitors are located. In addition, log files help detect disruptions that may interfere with the provision of our website. 

**Information We Share  **  
We do not disclose information except as described in this Privacy Notice. We will not sell, share, transfer, rent, use, or distribute your information for purposes other than those disclosed here unless required by law or as authorized by you or your employer. We may share the information you provide among our subsidiaries, affiliates and your employer or a third party as your employer instructs us, as appropriate or necessary in connection with the services. In addition, as part of the immigration consulting and legal services we have been directed to provide, Fragomen may disclose personal information to government agencies, your former, current, or prospective employer and its related entities. We may also share the information with certain service providers we have retained in connection with the services we provide, such as translators, education evaluation services, couriers, or other necessary entities. We take steps to require that service providers protect the information consistently with this Privacy Notice. These service providers are authorized to use the information only as necessary to perform services on our behalf or to comply with law or legal process. Where we have knowledge that a service provider processes your personal information in a manner contrary to this Privacy Notice, we will take reasonable steps to prevent or stop the processing. In addition, we may disclose information about you: (1) if we are required to do so by law or legal process, (2) to law enforcement authorities or other government officials, (3) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity; or (4) if this is necessary to protect the vital interests of any person. 

**How We Protect Personal Information  **  
We seek to ensure that any personal information that we hold about you is accurate, complete, current and otherwise reliable based on data you or an employer provide in order to provide the immigration consulting and legal services. We seek to collect personal information that is adequate, relevant and not excessive for these purposes. 

We maintain appropriate administrative, technical, and physical safeguards to protect against loss, misuse or unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction of personal information.   
We educate our employees and strive to maintain appropriate standards of conduct with regard to the protection of personal information.   
We take steps to require that third parties who assist in our provision of services abide by all applicable privacy and data protection laws and prohibit them from using your information other than in connection with the services they have been engaged to provide. 

**Information We Transfer  **  
To provide immigration consulting and legal services, we may transfer the personal information we collect to several countries, such as the United States or any other country in which Fragomen or its affiliates, subsidiaries, or service providers maintain facilities, which may not provide the same level of data protection as the laws in the country in which you reside. When we transfer your information to other countries, we will use, share and safeguard that information as described in this Privacy Notice. 

**Your Choices and Rights  **  
As set out above, Fragomen may collect certain information about you for purposes of providing immigration consulting and legal services. In the unlikely event that Fragomen wishes to use this information in a way that is incompatible with these purposes, we will notify, as applicable, either your employer on whose behalf we process your information or you if you have engaged Fragomen directly. We will respect your decision if subsequently your employer informs us or, where we notify you directly, you inform us that you wish to opt-out of personal information about you being processed for the new purpose. If sensitive personal information is involved we will only use your information for the new purpose if you actively communicate your consent to this processing to your employer or us, as applicable, in accordance with the requirements of applicable laws. We will follow the identical procedure if we disclose personal information to third parties that are expected to process the personal information for their own independent purposes. 

We also will assist our clients to provide you or provide you directly, as applicable, with reasonable access to your personal information and, where appropriate, with the ability to review and correct inaccuracies. We will use reasonable efforts to assist your employer respond to an access request or, where required under law, to respond directly to a valid access request within a reasonable period of time. To help protect your privacy and provide security, Fragomen takes reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access to information. To exercise these rights, please contact your employer or Fragomen, as applicable. 

**Updates to our Privacy Notice  **  
This Privacy Notice may be updated periodically without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our information practices. We will post a notice on our applicable websites or materials to advise of any significant changes to our Privacy Notice and indicate in the notice when it was most recently updated. While this Privacy Notice is designed to comply with the most stringent data privacy laws and represents “best practices,” in certain countries additional or different procedures not inconsistent with this Privacy Notice may apply as necessary to satisfy local legal requirements. 

**How to Contact Us  **  
If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Notice, please contact us by email at [dataprivacy@fragomen.com](mailto:dataprivacy@fragomen.com). You also may write to us at: 

Attn: Office of General Counsel   
Fragomen, Del Rey, Bernsen & Loewy, LLP   
90 Matawan Road   
P.O. Box 2001   
Matawan, New Jersey 07747   
USA 

_Last updated June 15, 2012_

___________________________________

**FRAGOMEN SAFE HARBOR PRIVACY NOTICE**

EFFECTIVE DATE: April 8, 2013 

Fragomen, Del Rey, Bernsen & Loewy, LLP and Fragomen Global LLP (collectively, “ **Fragomen** ”) comply with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework established by the United States Department of Commerce with respect to personal information that is transferred to or received by Fragomen in the U.S. from countries in the European Economic Area and Switzerland. 

Fragomen has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement with respect to such personal information. In addition, Fragomen may also apply more specific privacy requirements which are consistent with the Safe Harbor Frameworks. For example, personal information obtained from or relating to clients and their employees or former clients of Fragomen is subject to the terms of any specific privacy notice provided by Fragomen regarding such matter, applicable contractual arrangements or engagement letters, as well as governing laws and professional standards. Also, certain Fragomen websites may apply particular privacy policies regarding the collection and use of personal information by those websites, in each case any such particular policy being accessible on those websites. 

For further information about the Safe Harbor Program, and to view Fragomen’s certification, please see the United States Department of Commerce website at [www.export.gov/safeharbor](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor).

If you have any questions or comments about this policy, please contact us by email at [dataprivacy@fragomen.com](mailto:dataprivacy@fragomen.com). You also may write to us at: 

Attn: Office of General Counsel – Data Privacy Officer   
Fragomen, Del Rey, Bernsen & Loewy, LLP   
90 Matawan Road   
P.O. Box 2001   
Matawan, New Jersey 07747   
USA 

_Last Updated: June 19, 2013_

**ANTI-SLAVERY  and HUMAN TRAFFICKING STATEMENT**

We know that slavery, servitude, forced labour and human trafficking is a global and growing issue given the rapid rise in global migration, existing in every region in the world and in every type of economy, whether industrial, developing or in transition. No sector or industry can be considered immune or untainted.

Fragomen has a zero tolerance approach to modern slavery of any kind within our operations and supply chain. Our positive contribution to the work of our clients is matched by our commitment to running our own operations responsibly. We are committed to ensuring that slavery, human trafficking, child labour – indeed, any abuse of human rights – have no place in or around our organisation. We are proud of the steps we have taken to combat slavery and human trafficking and are pleased to reinforce that commitment through this statement.

**Our Organization’s structure**

Fragomen is a professional immigration services firm made up of law firms and consultancies in more than 40 offices worldwide and operating as Fragomen LLP, a limited liability partnership, in England, under English law. In countries where we do not have offices or in house practice groups, we work with carefully selected local advisors to deliver services to our clients in more than 170 countries.

Members of our Executive Committee and Leadership Team are responsible for managing the firm’s worldwide operations (including Fragomen LLP). These professionals drive Fragomen’s values, ethics, vision, client services, structure and support teams, and make certain that our firm remains compliant with all applicable legislation relating to employee terms and conditions, and ensures that the firm invests heavily in supporting the health and wellbeing of our staff across all jurisdictions in which we operate.

**Our Supply Chains**

We are committed to ensuring that there is no modern slavery or human trafficking in our supply chains or in any part of our business. Our Anti-slavery and Human Trafficking Policy reflects our commitment to acting ethically and with integrity in all our business relationships and to implementing and enforcing effective systems and controls to ensure slavery and human trafficking is not taking place any where in out supply chains.

**Due Diligence Process for Slavery and Human Trafficking**

As a professional services organisation, we consider the risk of modern slavery existing within our business to be low. However, to ensure that we are compliant with all applicable legislation we have carried out our own due diligence programme through a cross-functional working group.

As part of our initiative to identify and mitigate risk we have in place systems to:

  * Identify and assess potential risk areas in our supply chains.
  * Mitigate the risk of slavery and human trafficking occurring in our supply chains.
  * Monitor potential risk areas in our supply chains.
  * Protect whistle blowers.

**Supplier Adherence to our values and ethics**

We have zero tolerance to slavery and human trafficking. To ensure all those in our supply chain and contractors comply with our values and ethics we have in place a rigorous supply chain compliance programme.  
Training

We are currently focusing on raising internal awareness to enable the relevant members of staff to understand the requirements of the Modern Slavery Act and to give them the tools to flag potential issues.

Over time, we will seek to develop an e-learning solution for all our staff, which will ensure that Modern Slavery is targeted more persistently, regardless of staff turnover or changes in the supply chain.

A key focus for the next 12-18 months is to engage in more detail with our staff and our key suppliers.  
This statement is made pursuant to section 54(1) of the Modern Slavery Act 2015 and constitutes slavery and human trafficking statement for the financial year ending 31 December 2016.

Attn: Caron Pope  
Fragomen LLP  
95 Gresham St.  
London, EC2V 7NA  
United Kingdom

_Last Updated: December 2016_
